const quizzes = [
  {
    question: "Which war movie won the Academy Award for Best Picture in 2009?",
    choices: [
      "The Hurt Locker",
      "Saving Private Ryan",
      "Letters to Iwojima",
      "Inglorious Basterds"
    ],
    correctAnswer: "The Hurt Locker",
    imgURL: "assets/images/hurtlocker.gif",
    factoid:
      "The Hurt Locker was directed by Kathryn Bigelow, ex-wife of James Cameron who also produced Avatar in the same year. It was nominated for 9 Academy Awards and won 6 in 2009."
  },
  {
    question:
      "What was the name of the second Indiana Jones movie, released in 1984?",
    choices: [
      "Indiana Jones and the Kingdom of the Crystal Skull",
      "Raiders of the Lost Ark",
      "Indiana Jones and the Temple of Doom",
      "Indiana Jones and the Last Crusade"
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Indiana Jones and the Temple of Doom",
    imgURL: "assets/images/indianajones.gif",
    factoid:
      "Raiders of the Lost Ark came first, with Temple of Doom filmed as a prequel and Last Crusade as a sequel, with Crystal Skull filmed almost 20 years after that."
  },
  {
    question: "Which actress plays Katnis Everdeen in the Hunger Games?",
    choices: [
      "Jennifer Gardner",
      "Jennifer Lawrence",
      "Jennifer Aniston",
      "Jennifer Love Hewitt"
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Jennifer Lawrence",
    imgURL: "assets/images/hungergames.webp",
    factoid:
      "Jennifer Lawrence spent 15 days training on how to hold and shoot a bow with US olympiad, Khatuna Lorig, for her role. USA Archery membership swelled 84% after the movie."
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which English director was responsible for the epic movie Gladiator in 2000?",
    choices: [
      "Peter Jackson",
      "Wolfgang Peterson",
      "Ron Howard",
      "Ridley Scott"
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Ridley Scott",
    imgURL: "assets/images/gladiator.webp",
    factoid:
      "Ridley Scott is an English filmmaker, best known for his science fiction horror film, Alien (1979). He came up with another winner in Gladiator, clinching Best Picture, 21 years later."
  },
  {
    question:
      "What movie featured humans living in a simulated world to keep their sleeping body functioning as batteries for machines in the real world?",
    choices: ["The Truth", "The Matrix", "Gattaca", "The Island"],
    correctAnswer: "The Matrix",
    imgURL: "assets/images/thematrix.webp",
    factoid:
      "The Matrix features a scene where the protagonist, Neo, takes a pill and ends up waking up in the real world after, where he is plugged and the electrical impulses generated by his heartbeat is sucked for power by the machines."
  },
  {
    question:
      "For what movie did Leonardo DiCaprio finally get an Academy Award for since his debut in Titanic in 1997?",
    choices: [
      "The Aviator",
      "Inception",
      "The Wolf of Wall Street",
      "The Revenant"
    ],
    correctAnswer: "The Revenant",
    imgURL: "assets/images/therevenant.webp",
    factoid:
      "Leonardo DiCaprio has been nominated 5 times for an Oscar over the span of 23 years since he first appeared in the movies, and finally won it in the Revenant in 2016."
  },
  {
    question:
      "How many movies did Brad Pitt and Angelina Jolie star in together?",
    choices: ["1", "2", "3", "4"],
    correctAnswer: "2",
    imgURL: "assets/images/mrandmrssmith.webp",
    factoid:
      "Even though they were once the power Hollywood couple and are both famous actors, they only worked on 2 films together: Mr and Mrs Smith (2005) and By The Sea (2015)"
  },
  {
    question: " “You had me at hello” was a famous line from which movie?",
    choices: [
      "Forrest Gump",
      "Jerry McGuire",
      "When Harry met Sally",
      "The Notebook"
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Jerry McGuire",
    imgURL: "assets/images/jerrymcguire.webp",
    factoid:
      "At the end of the movie, when Jerry expresses his love in a long-winded speech to Dorothy, Dorothy's romantic reply was memorialised in that simple phrase."
  },
  {
    question:
      "How many Spiderman movies are there since the release of Spider-Man in 2002?",
    choices: ["5", "6", "8", "10"],
    correctAnswer: "8",
    imgURL: "assets/images/spiderman.gif",
    factoid:
      "Spiderman (2002), Spiderman 2 (2004), Spiderman 3 (2007), The Amazing Spiderman (2012), The Amazing Spiderman 2 (2014), Spiderman: Homecoming (2017), Into the Spider-Verse(2018), Spiderman: Far from Home(2019)"
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following actors did not play Batman?",
    choices: ["Michael Keaton", "Val Kilmer", "Adam East", "Christian Bale"],
    correctAnswer: "Adam East",
    imgURL: "assets/images/adamwest.webp",
    factoid:
      "Adam West was the original Batman in the series Batman aired 1966 to 1968. Famed for its comical fight scenes, this was the non-serious take on the superhero before future adaptations took a darker turn."
  }
];
